<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Man Pages on Dhruv's Blog</title><link>http://typdef.com/tags/man-pages/</link><description>Recent content in Man Pages on Dhruv's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://typdef.com/tags/man-pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linux Filesystem Hierarchy</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/man-hier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/man-hier/</guid><description>It is often tough to know where certain kinds of files or applications are in the Linux files system.
It is complicated due to historical reasons, and different distributions often put their files in different locations.
A good way to know where things are, or where things go, is by referring to your distribution&amp;rsquo;s man pages.
man hier</description></item><item><title>A list of (unix) environment variables on your system</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/environ-variables/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 22:20:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/environ-variables/</guid><description>On Linux, man 7 environ describes a number of common environment variables, and gives references to other man pages which describe them in more detail. Equivalents exist on other systems; see for example the FreeBSD version. (Historically, Unix V7 had an equivalent in section 5; the BSDs have had this in section 7 since at least BSD4.3.)
In general, to look through all the man pages which mention a given environment variable, you can use man -K, which runs a full-text search in all the installed man pages’ sources, with the -w and -i options (which respectively list man pages instead of viewing them, and match the strings’ case):</description></item></channel></rss>