<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on typdef's Blog</title><link>http://typdef.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on typdef's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 22:45:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://typdef.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Change the time zone data on Linux</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/change-time-zone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 22:45:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/change-time-zone/</guid><description>The main step to do here is to configure the tzdata package
Then choose the appropriate timezone info
Ubuntu sudo dpkg-reconfigure tzdata</description></item><item><title>Running oneoff process in the background over ssh</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/running-procs-bg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 18:30:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/running-procs-bg/</guid><description>Imagine a situation where you need to download a large file from the internet to a remote server.
You run curl https://download.com -o download and logout of the ssh server. Big mistake! you come back hours later just to see that the download ended as soon as you logged out.
The nohup command helps here. nohup stands for no hold up, and will run the command without any external interruptions. you can further run the command in the background using &amp;amp;.</description></item><item><title>Linux Filesystem Hierarchy</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/man-hier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:00:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/man-hier/</guid><description>It is often tough to know where certain kinds of files or applications are in the Linux files system.
It is complicated due to historical reasons, and different distributions often put their files in different locations.
A good way to know where things are, or where things go, is by referring to your distribution&amp;rsquo;s man pages.
man hier</description></item><item><title>Get a Brief of Ip command (with Color)</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/cli/ip-brief-output/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 11:25:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/cli/ip-brief-output/</guid><description>The default ip addr command, which gives you ip address of your device, is cluttered with alot of values, which may not be useful to you. To quickly get the output, you can pass the -br or --brief argument, which outputs a brief of the network statistic.
Additionally you can get color output by passing the -c or --color argument.</description></item><item><title>Laggy SSH-Server connections on Laptops</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/ssh/laggy-ssh-server-with-iw-powersave/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 20:12:56 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/ssh/laggy-ssh-server-with-iw-powersave/</guid><description>When using a laptop as a server, if the SSH connection is laggy, it may be because of a wireless card’s power-saving feature.
You can turn this feature off by issuing the command
iw &amp;lt;devname&amp;gt; set power_save off
You can view the status of iw using the command
iw &amp;lt;devname&amp;gt; get power_save
and the device name &amp;lt;devname&amp;gt; using the command ip a
iw is used to show / manipulate wireless devices and their configuration</description></item><item><title>Linux as a Backend</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/linux-as-backend/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 22:15:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/linux-as-backend/</guid><description>After accessing the linux server in the creative lab and then setting up my blog site on a VBox VM, using port-binding, I have started to feel like using whatever Desktop OS (Windows/MacOS/Linux) is just fine.
Why SSH Port Forwarding gives you Superpowers
Most of the usage of this kind of work will be via the terminal itself.
I am however still struggling with how to use desktop linux, so as to be that one guy who propogates Linux use on the desktop.</description></item><item><title>./ in Linux</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/dotslash-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/linux/dotslash-linux/</guid><description>So, why exactly does ./executable work in Linux and Unix (and .\ in windows)?
The ./ translates to: in the current directory (dot(.) : this, slash(/) : directory)
Now recall that there is a variable called $PATH in all operating system shells.
The role of this variable is to store the path to all the places where system binaries are stored (for eg in /bin or /usr/bin or /sbin)
Also remember that shells can then take these binaries as inputs and directly run them like</description></item></channel></rss>