<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on typdef's Blog</title><link>http://typdef.com/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on typdef's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://typdef.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/git/git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 12:00:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/git/git/</guid><description>Some Conventions
repository(repo) -&amp;gt; basically just a folder, which has all your code in it
local repo -&amp;gt; The folder that is On your computer
remote repo -&amp;gt; The folder that is on some git server (or on a server, basically not on your computer)
origin is the git repo, master is the branch of the repo you want to push to.
Before we proceed, please also check the help pages and the man pages for the topics, they go beyond these basics and explaing in more depth</description></item><item><title>Forget git history</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/git/forget-git-hist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/git/forget-git-hist/</guid><description>To remove the git history git checkout --orphan tmp # create a temporary branch git add -A # Add all files and commit them git commit -m &amp;#39;Add files&amp;#39; git branch -D main # Deletes the master branch git branch -m main # Rename the current branch to master git push -f origin main # Force push master branch to Git server</description></item><item><title>Git Credential Manager</title><link>http://typdef.com/posts/git/git-credential-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>http://typdef.com/posts/git/git-credential-manager/</guid><description>Github removed the https login with username password to push/pull code.
Now you have to generate a personal access token and use that token instead of the password for those operations.
This brings us to git credential manger, you can save the username and password (or the personal access token) with git for https logins, so that you dont have to input it again and again.
You can do this with</description></item></channel></rss>